- I'm busy!
- "Duty calls."
"I've been trying to get you on the phone.
Open the door."
Does that board have you
any closer to catching Red John?
I don't know.
I keep getting interrupted.
What I need is radio silence,
Lisbon, for a week. If you can.
The dead body at LaRoche's house
won't wait that long.
J.J.s?
He asked for you specifically
on the case.
Hey, boss.
So LaRoche came home early
on a red eye from New York.
He saw the flashlights and surprised
two robbers breaking into the safe.
- That's when the shooting started.
- Where's the other one?
Escaped out the back.
They wore masks.
It was dark.
LaRoche didn't see much.
Oh, they hit the hummels.
- Is LaRoche okay?
- He sustained a minor hit.
Anything missing from the safe?
Nope. He stopped them
before they could take anything.
You know, we can have
someone handle the dog.
Oh, yeah, I know.
- There's no I.D. on the body.
- Well, maybe not government issue
but there's a lot of information here.
Like these black spots on his fingertips.
Dead tissue.
And his eyes are very
inflamed, too.
- Maybe he was on drugs.
- Just...
Nice one, Lisbon.
Ibuprofen.
I'm gonna guess this man was suffering
from rheumatoid arthritis.
Well, if you're gonna
get in a gunfight
it's best to get in one
with an arthritic shooter.
- Where is LaRoche?
- He's waiting in the ambulance.
He won't let the paramedics take him
for treatment until he talks to you.
Well, excuse me.
V.I.P.
Hey!
J.J.
I see you bought a new safe.
Apparently it's not safe enough.
- Excuse us, please.
- Yes, sir.
I'm gonna cut to the chase,
Mr. Jane.
- I was not forthcoming with Rigsby.
- They took something.
- My Tupperware box.
- Yeah, I figured.
Been hiding that box
for nine years.
I thought you were the only one
that knew of its existence.
But after the gunfire ended
the box was missing
and this was in its place.
"Drop the case.
You have until tonight."
What case?
I'm investigating a security leak
inside CBI.
The leak will turn the Tupperware
over to authorities if I don't back off.
You know what'll happen
if they unseal that box.
- I do.
- Of course you do.
- I didn't take it.
- I know that, Patrick.
It's your favorite blackmail device.
Your puppet mastery over me ends if...
its contents becomes public knowledge.
I never thought of you
as a puppet.
You ever thought of me
as a friend?
This is difficult to ask.
I need your help.
- Please.
- Sure. I'll find your Tupperware.
I would appreciate that.
As would my mother.
You can take me now.
So what's in the Tupperware box?
I don't know.
"Two years ago, I hired a petty thief"
to break into LaRoche's safe
for a list of Red John suspects.
Yeah, I know.
I had to slug the guy
in front of his lawyer
to keep you out of jail.
Cost me six months
in anger management.
Yeah, and I hope
you learned something.
My point is
he opened the safe
- and he saw a Tupperware box.
- Which was stolen this morning.
To blackmail LaRoche
into dropping his investigation.
What investigation?
Well, apparently there's
a security leak inside the CBI.
Well, maybe your thief took it.
No, LaRoche's new safe
is way out of his league.
In any case, the missing plasticware
has the power to end LaRoche's career.
- And you really don't know what's inside?
- No, I don't.
But LaRoche
doesn't know that.
So while I'm busy with him,
why don't you assign
Rigsby and Van Pelt
to find out what's in the box?
Our job is to catch
the criminal who got away
not protect some CBI agent
who might be dirty.
So much for
the anger management training.
If we can solve the mystery
of LaRoche's secret
it will lead us
to the missing criminal.
Why don't you just ask
LaRoche what's in the box?
He's not gonna tell me voluntarily.
It's embarrassing to him
and deeply personal.
- And it's in Tupperware?
- Yes.
How could you not want
to investigate?
LaRoche told Jane he had
the box for nine years.
Dig into his past.
Look for significant events.
And check out his mother. LaRoche made
a strange reference to her.
The Tupperware's a clue.
Why hide something in Tupperware?
I don't know. Keep it fresh?
Nothing stays fresh
for nine years.
Well, maybe LaRoche needed a box
and the Tupperware was handy.
No. Tupperware's never handy.
It's always in the wrong drawer.
And when you do find it,
the lid's always missing.
- Right? I hate that.
- Yeah.
Uh, don't let LaRoche know
you have knowledge of the box.
That's a confidence
between he and Jane.
- Okay.
- We got a hit on the dead guy.
Will Parsons.
Local family man, married.
Owns a locksmith shop in El Dorado Hills.
Clean record.
All right, let's go talk to the wife.
This has to be a mistake.
Will is a locksmith, not a killer. He...
He was on a house call,
fixing a rusted dead bolt.
The key snapped off in the lock.
Your husband was part of a 2-man team
that broke into a residential home.
He brought his gun,
and he fired at our agent.
If Will did that,
then somebody made him.
Yea... maybe they were holding
a gun on him. That's possible, right?
When was the last time
you saw your husband, ma'am?
When he left the house
last night at 11:00.
- Did you see him take his gun?
- No. No.
Do you know anyone who might have
hired your husband to break into a safe?
Oh, no.
What is happening here?
I have suspected a security leak
inside CBI for months.
Too many high-profile
suspects evading arrest.
Really? Haven't noticed.
Well, that's because you stop at nothing
to close cases for your team.
Why, thank you.
Other CBI agents,
they have, uh, principles.
I leaned into that one.
Miguel Leyva.
Sinaloa cartel.
He controls drug corridors
throughout the East Bay.
Two months ago, a CBI task force
was set for a bust.
And when they raided
his warehouse
three tons of cocaine
disappeared without a trace.
- Someone in the CBI tipped him off?
- Him and others before him.
That was my instinct, and it was
confirmed by the arrest of this man.
Tommy Volker.
He was always a step ahead
of your team and I found out why.
He had a secret
cell phone account.
Now, in the days before his arrest
that number was called six times...
from inside CBI.
- Well, at least you have a suspect.
- Of which I am not aware.
The thief who got away.
Huh? You find the thief
you find the leak.
Before tonight. That's when my blackmailer
will expose the truth about me.
Well, like you said,
I'll stop at nothing.
You know what's
in that box, Patrick.
- What do you think of me?
- You...
You're gonna have to be
a little more, uh, specific.
Am I a monstrosity to you?
A monstrosity?
No.
I mean...
You're... you're interesting
and you're complex.
- I am?
- And obviously creative. Tupperware...
Well, I suppose
that's true.
I've been afraid to ask that
until now.
Excuse me.
Found something.
Nine years ago, LaRoche's mother
was physically and sexually assaulted.
The attack lasted two hours.
She said she begged
for mercy the whole time
- but... her rapist just ignored her.
- Wow. Did she survive?
Three months later,
she took her life.
Oh... poor LaRoche.
What does all this have to do
with a plastic container?
What if there was evidence inside?
Scott Saynay. The man convicted
of raping LaRoche's mother.
He's serving a 12-year
sentence in Folsom.
What if LaRoche planted
evidence to assure his conviction?
- Like what?
- I don't know. His mother's blood?
I mean, it says here that
the only physical evidence
linking Saynay to the crime
is her blood on his clothes.
Why would LaRoche
want to keep that?
Maybe he thought he'd need it again
if Saynay got out on appeal.
Oh... this is crazy.
How can the boss possibly
expect us to solve this?
I don't know, but I really want
to know what's in that box.
Yeah, me, too.
I wonder if he knows.
Hi. Can I get
a medium coffee, please?
- Lisbon. I was looking for you.
- Hey, Brenda.
Any developments
on the LaRoche break-in?
Not yet, no. Why?
The head of our Internal Affairs division
was shot inside his home this morning.
We need to get out
in front of the case.
Well, that's what I'm trying to do.
I'm heading to the autopsy now.
I mean from a public perspective.
We can't allow people to believe
there's corruption brewing inside CBI.
Is that what people believe?
There's been some chatter
in the local blogosphere.
- I don't read blogs.
- Well, you should.
It's easy to forget, but we work
in the state capital.
Now I just came
from Bertram's office.
He agrees with me
that a TV interview
with a friendly reporter
is a win-win for the Bureau.
- Well, let's win.
- I'll get back to you with details.
No obstruction of the airway.
The mucosa of the epiglottis, glottis,
and major bronchi are anatomic.
Thanks for coming by.
Since when do we attend autopsies?
Well, since we have a deadline to confirm
my diagnosis at the crime scene.
No injuries to the respiratory
system that I can see.
Rheumatoid arthritis, right?
And?
Well, this man... was at war with his body,
Lisbon, specifically his hands.
Um, would you explain, Doc?
See the swelling and inflammation
around the wrists?
It created a compression
of the medial nerve inside.
Carpal tunnel, basically.
Any repetitive use of the subject's hands
would have caused great pain.
- A locksmith who can't use his hands?
- There's more.
I noticed thickening and scarring
of the pericardium...
that's the sac-like structure
around the heart.
- You can see it here.
- I'll take your word for it.
Chronic chest pain and shortness of breath
were a way of life for this man.
Thanks, Doc.
I don't get it. Why would somebody hire
a disabled thief to rob a safe?
Well, you wouldn't.
Not knowingly.
Now you said Parsons here
owned a locksmith business?
- Yeah, with his wife.
- I'd like to meet her.
Mom's been a wreck
since your visit this morning.
She's taking the news
really hard.
- She and my dad were crazy close.
- Oh, we'll try to keep this brief.
Mom? The CBI agents want to ask you
a few more questions.
Okay, fine.
Jenna, this is Patrick Jane.
- Hi. I'm sorry for your loss.
- Thank you.
Sarah, could you please
make us some tea?
Please.
I told Sarah her father had been shot
but I didn't mention the robbery.
I'm counting on you
to straighten that out.
Oh, we're working on it.
Quite a safe collection
your husband had.
Well, he had more.
But we had to sell some off
when the economy took a dive.
Yeah.
Yeah, well, most people
collect for sentimental reasons.
It's an attempt to trigger
a fond memory.
I'm gonna guess... I'm gonna
go out on a limb here
and guess that your husband's collection
started with this little fella.
Will found that when he was 7.
It was locked, so he was dying
to know what was inside
and he spent months trying every
possible number combination
until finally one misty
morning, it opened.
- What was inside?
- I don't remember.
That's a disappointment.
No, Lisbon, it doesn't matter
what was inside.
The exciting part is
the mystery of not knowing.
It's what makes
the journey memorable.
Will spent his entire career
following that journey.
It's what made him become a locksmith.
Jenna, we found out that he was
losing the use of his hands.
Why didn't you tell us
about that earlier?
I didn't think of it.
You'd just told me
the man I spent
my entire life with was dead.
Which I still don't understand.
The first step is finding out
who he broke into that house with.
- Did he have any employees?
- No. It was just Will.
He wanted to hire
a good locksmith
to cut down on his workload, but he couldn't
find anybody up to his standards.
- That's incredibly valuable.
- You know about safes?
- Do you have the combination for this?
- No. Will kept those in his head.
I was hoping you'd say that.
- Wait! What're you doing? What?
- Jane! Stop it!
Mom! What's he doing?
What are you, crazy?
That's airtight!
Then you'd better
get to work then.
Mom! We have to do something.
What do we do?
I've got it.
How's she know
how to do that?
Your father was losing
the use of his hands.
He needed help, so he taught
everything he knew
to the woman he trusted most.
How come
I don't know this?
Well, I imagine your father
was a proud man, too.
Too proud to let anyone know
his wife was doing his job for him.
Et voila!
Okay, take it.
You're gonna have to come
with us now.
Turn around.
Put your hands behind your back.
What, you're arresting her?
For what?
Breaking and entering,
safecracking, and armed robbery.
That sound about right?
I'm the one who opened
your agent's safe.
It was a Sargent and Greenleaf lock
and they can take hours
and Will, just...
moving his fingers hurt so much.
And who hired you to break
into Agent LaRoche's home?
Will never said.
He just said somebody called
and offered him a lot of money
to open a residential safe.
- What were you asked to steal?
- A plastic container.
I don't know what was in it.
I didn't ask.
Where is it, ma'am?
- Where's the plastic container you stole?
- We, um...
We had a drop point.
A storm drain in Woodley Park.
When you left the shop
this morning, I...
drove to the park
and left the container.
- And you never looked inside?
- No. I just wanted it to be done with.
"My husband lost his life
over that stupid box."
- You think we're too late?
- Never know unless you try.
Did your contact say
where the storm drain was?
Near a warning sign.
Someone's already been here.
There.
- CBI! Down on the ground!
- Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Put your hands
where I can see them! Down!
- What'd I do?
- Now! On your knees! Get down now!
He's usually a very calm man.
Now do as he says.
- Okay. Just don't shoot.
- Secure the container, please.
Should probably check it
to be sure.
- Daddy?
- It's okay, buddy.
Everything's gonna be all right.
Banana and peanut butter.
You're a lucky kid.
Looks tasty.
I am very sorry, sir.
Have a nice day.
Come on, buddy.
Let's get out of here.
My time is running out.
Whatever happens, I want
to thank you for trying to help me.
Well, truth is, you're
a hard man not to help, LaRoche.
You're like a Shar-Pei puppy
that's rolled onto its back.
- You have to rub its belly.
- You're mocking me.
No, no, I'm happy
to rub your belly.
- That won't be necessary.
- I hope not.
Should be here somewhere.
- Uh, what was the name again?
- Scott Saynay.
He's serving a 12-year sentence
for rape and indecent assault.
Oh, here it is. Scott Saynay was here.
Early release. Six weeks ago.
- Oh. Where's he now?
- Should be in here somewhere.
Sorry for the mess,
but the Supreme Court just ruled
that prison overcrowding
is unconstitutional.
- What a bother.
- I know, right?
We have to reduce our numbers
by 1,800 this year.
Saynay was one of
the lucky ones.
Looks like the release file
was forwarded.
You could find him
through his parole officer.
- And who would that be?
- It's in the release file.
But I could put a trace on it.
Might take a few days.
Yeah, we don't have a few days.
Uh, maybe we could talk
to Saynay's last cellmate.
Oh! That's a good idea.
Let's see who that was.
Yes. Ahh...
Okay, should be in here
somewhere.
According to the records, you were
Scott Saynay's last roommate?
Saynay? Y-yeah, sure,
I remember him.
Easiest cellie I ever had.
Spent most nights writing
letters to his ma.
Did Saynay ever give you a sense
that he felt wrongly accused or set up?
Nah. He wasn't fighting any drama.
Not that you'd know it if he was.
- My boy wasn't much of a talker.
- What's so funny?
Ah, you'd have to meet Saynay
to fully appreciate his quiet nature.
Did he ever mention
a plastic container to you?
- What plastic container?
- I guess he didn't trust him enough.
- No, clearly.
- What are you talking about?
We're trying to locate
an airtight plastic box.
Your cellmate knew all about it.
It was hidden in a safe for nine years
but a man was killed
stealing it this morning.
Well, I'll be damned.
Wait. You know
what's in the box?
Well, I can guess.
Can't you?
- Oh, we want to hear your guess.
- Nothing in that for me
except I'd be pissing off
the owner of the box
and who wants to mess
with a maniac like that?
I'm done answering
their questions.
Scott Saynay, convicted
nine years ago
of raping and beating
LaRoche's mother.
She committed suicide
three months later.
That certainly qualifies
as a dramatic event in his life.
He just got out of prison.
We're trying to track him down.
Other than being an extreme
form of lowlife
what else did you learn
about him?
All we have are his arrest files
but there's nothing surprising.
He's a high school dropout,
unemployed.
Multiple burglary arrests.
He was on antidepressants the night
he attacked Mrs. LaRoche.
Then maybe he hired the locksmith
to open LaRoche's safe.
No. The break-in is connected
to LaRoche's internal investigation.
That, I'm certain of.
So we still don't know
what's in the box or who has it?
Okay, Teresa. Reporter's
here for your interview.
Ah, Sacramento's most
eligible singles
or should I say,
sexy spinsters of Sacramento?
Bertram wants to put a public
face on the LaRoche break-in.
Why?
To assure the public that we are not
rattled by criminal attacks on our people.
But LaRoche was rattled.
He was shot.
Just... let me do what I do.
You do what you do.
Whatever that is.
Lisbon, this way, please.
You only have 15 minutes.
Let's get this thing going.
You're the boss, Brenda.
- Really?
- Ah, I just let her think so.
We haven't officially met.
Mason Braverman.
Teresa Lisbon.
I have anything in my teeth?
- No, you're good. You're good.
- Okay, good. Let's do it.
This is the second time
Agent LaRoche's home
has been broken into, isn't it?
"Yes, it is."
What's he hiding in there?
Jimmy Hoffa?
Uh, we don't know why
Agent LaRoche's home was targeted.
He killed one of the robbers
in a gunfight.
We have the other one in custody
and we expect to have
some information soon.
You're certainly having more luck
than the CBI task force that
botched the Miguel Leyva raid.
We heard the dangerous cartel boss is free
because someone tipped him off.
- "That's not my case."
- Okay. Turn off the camera.
We agreed to a line
of questioning, Mason.
Uh, no.
- In exchange, I promised you...
- A line of questioning...
- access and an exclusive story.
- Which I never agreed to, Brenda.
Why don't I just step out
while you two clear this up?
Teresa, be patient.
I can always call Channel 10.
- It's your choice.
- No, I'm good.
So, how does this home invasion
affect other CBI agents?
The targeting
of Agent LaRoche's home...
is stark evidence that
no law enforcement officer
"is ever truly off duty.
We're all targets."
"But J.J. LaRoche chose
to be a CBI agent"
"which is a life
of serving other people."
"We all know the game,
and we all accept the risks."
Heard you had some
news on the case.
The phone company just confirmed
that a call was made
from the CBI
to the locksmith's shop.
LaRoche is right.
We've got an internal leak.
That's not news, Lisbon.
A phone extension would be news.
Well, they could only trace it
to the general switchboard.
We're still walking around blind, Lisbon.
And we're pressed for time.
LaRoche is pressed for time.
We're doing fine.
Hey, boss.
I might have a lead.
I found this newspaper
story in the archives.
It ran seven years ago.
"Will Parsons likes to play safe"?
It's a local profile
on Parsons and his collection.
Same year, he entered a national
safecracking competition. Placed seventh.
So you're thinking
that the CBI leak read this article
and knew that Parsons
could do the job?
It's a safe bet.
- That's funny.
- What is?
Never mind.
All right, see who else
is logged into the archive
and see if any CBI personnel are long-time
subscribers to the "Weekly."
Uh, I just may have
saved you the trouble.
Uh... look at the masthead.
Specifically, look who
the managing editor was
at the "Sacramento Weekly"
seven years ago.
Brenda Shettrick?
- No way. Brenda?
- Makes sense.
Most information inside CBI
runs through Shettrick.
With time, I can build a case, but...
- time is passing quickly.
- We always have time.
You know how long it takes me
to solve a case?
However long I have.
But in certain situations,
when I'm in a true pinch, such as this
there are compromises
that need to be made.
What kind of compromises?
Well, for instance, I could... I could
bring down Shettrick before tonight
but I will have to enlist the help
of Lisbon and the team.
No. Nobody can know
about the plastic box
or that it was taken
from my safe.
They already know.
I had to confide in Lisbon
that a very valuable box
was stolen from you
but I did not tell her
what was inside, I swear.
You had no right to reveal
its existence at all.
Lisbon is my partner.
Allegiances, loyalties...
Yes, of course. I...
What was I... thinking?
I understand. You and Lisbon,
you are trusted friends.
You do what you will
Mr. Jane.
That's what you'll do anyway.
J.J., come on.
Don't be like that.
If we're gonna catch Shettrick,
we need to move now.
All we have is Shettrick's
name on a masthead.
- I don't want to rush to judgment.
- Well, nobody rushed.
We took our time to judgment.
But now we're here,
and we need to act.
Hey, if we don't arrest her by tonight
she is going to expose LaRoche.
- Expose him for what?
- I couldn't tell you.
Have you ever thought that maybe
LaRoche's secret should be known?
Endlessly.
But I have come to the conclusion
that whatever happened,
he has punished himself enough.
- I still don't know about Shettrick.
- Yes, you do. In your gut, you know.
She sold you out to Volker.
You know that.
Her actions almost led
to the murder of an 8-year-old boy.
For once in your life, Lisbon,
don't be the voice of reason.
Be the voice of wrath.
All right.
How do we get the bitch?
Sorry, excuse me.
Uh, big to-do in the bullpen.
Lisbon needs help
handling the press.
What's the press doing...
oh, Jane!
Stop!
Tell me what's going on.
Uh, you remember
the drug lord that got away?
- Miguel Leyva.
- Well, CBI found his secret estate.
According to intel, he's sitting poolside
right now with a frisky blonde,
meatball sub
and a fresh shipment of drugs.
- What intel?
- Oh, I don't know.
But the Rapid Response Team
is about to conduct a raid
and that TV reporter
is getting in the way.
- What TV reporter?
- The one from today.
Lisbon invited him
to ride along on the bust.
For God sake, why?
Well... good P.R.
for the Bureau, I don't know.
I guess that's what
she thought you wanted.
Well, I...
Look, we can't let Leyva get away
this time.
We'll stack up on the forward door
with cover on all the windows.
I want a dynamic entry,
shock lock breach, bang and clear.
Guys, she's here.
It's time to start moving
- Let's roll.
- Let's not.
Turn the camera off.
This hasn't been cleared.
Yes, it has. I just left Bertram's office
and he says it's a win-win.
He just wants you to shepherd
our TV colleagues here.
No wonder you didn't want me
asking about Miguel Leyva.
You knew all along
a raid was in the works.
Well, of course.
Okay, just let me make
a phone call before we go.
We don't have time.
You're holding us up. Let's go.
Here's your vest. If you hurry,
you can make the 6:00 news.
Point the camera away from me.
Buh-bye!
Bring back a drug lord!
"This is a high-risk operation."
Surprise, speed,
and domination are key.
Our goals are to clear any threats and
prevent the destruction of any evidence.
Excuse me, what are you doing?
I told you I need
to cancel an appointment.
There's no outside communications
during an operation.
It's standard procedure.
Great.
Moving out.
Remember the tactical plan.
You three stay with Karl.
You want us with?
- Shouldn't we wait in the van?
- Bertram approved full access.
This is great, Brenda.
You're the best.
Stay focused on the breach team.
- Wait!
- Shh! Quiet!
I left my Kevlar vest in the van.
Then you hold right here.
We can't wait for you.
Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
"Yeah. What up?"
Miguel, it's Brenda Shettrick.
Don't talk. Listen.
They're about to break down
your door.
Now, I will make it go away just
like I did with the last raid.
Just don't say anything
to them.
"Slow down, woman.
What are you talking about?"
No time. Here they come.
Police! Search warrant!
Stand away from the door!
- Is it clear?!
- "Yeah, we're clear."
Hey.
"What's going on?
Get that away from me."
What are you doing here?
Where's Miguel Leyva?
Well, probably relaxing at his pad
wherever the hell that is.
Oh, this place is on the market
but you're gonna need to save
your pennies to post bail.
You're welcome to join us, Brenda.
- We were just reviewing the footage.
- What footage?
Very telegenic.
Don't you think?
"Don't talk. Listen. They're about
to break down your door."
"I will make it go away just
like I did with the last raid."
"Just don't say anything
to them."
You promised me an exclusive.
You weren't kidding.
How much did Miguel Leyva pay you
to tip him off about the drug raid?
- "Go to hell."
- Excellent.
You know how this works, Brenda.
- It'll go a lot easier if you just...
- I do know how this works.
That's what you tell the sheep
on their way to slaughter.
Why do they bleat?
I never understood that when
I watched your interrogations.
- I want a lawyer.
- Well, I guess she's too smart.
Not that smart. We have her
on tape tipping off a cartel boss.
Same way she tipped off Tommy Volker.
She's going down.
- I just wish I knew why.
- Well, I don't think she's gonna tell you.
But I will.
You don't know
the first thing about me.
You were an East Coast prep girl.
College? Uh, Barnard.
Or maybe Mount Holyoke
- for the horseback riding trails.
- She does like horses.
You were a romantic.
You moved to the state capital
because you wanted to expose
fakes and frauds and fall in love,
and write stories in coffee shops.
- She does like coffee.
- A lot of people like coffee.
Here's the one problem...
you couldn't write.
Your skill set was more
managing editor.
Managing editors are the second
highest ranking position at a newspaper.
Yes. The allure of power.
It's why you joined the CBI
so you could rub elbows
with all the big players in town.
You're so off.
Never did fall in love.
Well, at least, uh...
No one fell in love with you.
So you found your thrills
in the arms of power
trading favors
and inside information
to anyone who'd have you.
And in the end, you became
exactly what you hated.
Just another political phony
on the take.
Van Pelt and I made a bet
what's in the plastic ware.
Animal, a vegetable, or mineral.
What do you think?
Check the file cabinet.
Van Pelt says animal.
I say vegetable.
- Van Pelt wins.
- No way!
If it was biological,
you'd freeze it.
Tupperware, it's for food storage.
Has to be vegetable.
- Like what, broccoli?
- I don't know.
Hey, hey, hey.
Check it out.
It exists.
Yeah, it's a box.
Let's go.
Hang on. Don't you care
what's inside?
No.
I think there's something
stuck to the bottom.
- Is that yours to open?
- I was just gonna sneak a peek.
- Thank you for keeping my secret.
- Eh. It was easy.
I'm afraid Brenda Shettrick can still bring
me down with what she knows.
- She won't.
- How can you be sure?
Shettrick likes to trade.
She's cutting a deal with the D.A.
right now to give up her drug lord.
She told Lisbon she'd
forget about Tupperware
if we forget about
blackmail charges.
How did Shettrick know about
the box to begin with?
Only you and I knew
of its existence.
You... and I...
and...
Donny Culpepper.
Small-time thief I hired
to break into your safe.
She must have bought
the information from him.
Well...
This concludes our business
together, Mr. Jane.
I certainly hope not.
You've never asked me why I keep this.
I appreciate that.
- But I suppose you must wonder.
- I wouldn't be human if I didn't.
I hold on to this box
as a warning.
It reminds me of the depths to which
a man can sink if he lets himself.
And...
It reminds me of my mother.
- Good night, J.J.
- Good night, Patrick.
So? Did you look in the box?
- And violate the man's privacy?
- Yes.
What's inside the box is of
far less significance to me
than what the box represents.
I just want to know why you bent over
backwards for that man.
What's important to know
is that a man will go
to extreme lengths to find peace.
- As I must do now.
- What are you talking about?
Until I come out of this room,
I need to be alone, Lisbon.
Alone. No interruptions.
- But...
- No distractions.
- Please.
- Okay.
- Do what you have to do.
- Thank you.
- Hey. Is Jane up there?
- Yeah, but he's busy. What's up?
He asked me to tell him
when I found
the ex-con who assaulted
LaRoche's mother.
Oh, no need. It's over now.
You want to hear
something creepy, though?
The rapist lives with his mom.
- Uh, can I get that address?
- Sure.
Mrs. Saynay, one of my colleagues
called you earlier. I'm with the CBI.
- You can call me Judith.
- I'm Teresa Lisbon.
You people, need my son's help
to help you solve a case?
Is that right?
To help solve a mystery,
at least.
Scott! Get down here!
You got a visitor!
He needs a little
extra motivation sometimes.
How long has your son
lived with you?
Came straight out of jail.
I'd pretend to be flattered...
Uh, but I'm all that he's got.
Vice versa, too.
Hello. I'm Agent Lisbon
with the CBI.
I need you to answer
some questions for me.
You mean you...you...
- You don't know?
- What?
Scott hasn't...
spoken in nine years.
Well, why?
Well, the... the day before his trial
somebody broke into his apartment
while he was sleeping, and...
they injected him with a sedative
and cut out his tongue.
The police, they never figured out
who did it you know, or why, or...
And they never found
his tongue.